after two verse 34 and 35 the Bible says
and Simeon blessed them and said unto
Mary his mother behold this child is set
is what everyone set for the fall and
rising again of many in Israel and for a
sign which shall be spoken against this
verse looks like a ominous text it's a
strange text because here we're being
told that Jesus the child is set for the
Fall
now how many of you like falling all
right how many of you get really
irritated when you trip over something
that happened to be in your way how many
of you would not be too happy if you
knew that that thing that was in your
way was intentionally put there to trip
you up this is what the text appears to
be saying behold this child is what
everyone set for the fall that word set
is translated as lead in the following
verses Luke chapter 24 verse 12 when it
speaks about that the sight was going
into the tomb and seeing the linen cloth
laid there to the side the linen cloth
was intentionally laid to the side it
speaks about this same word is used in
John 11 verse 41 where it says that
Lazarus was laid in the tomb he was
intentionally put there in Matthew 3
verse 10 now the axe is laid to the root
of the tree it's translated as sent in
Matthew 5:14 a city set on a hill the
same word is used set when it's speaking
about the water basins you remember
where Jesus turned the six water basins
into wine it says that these water
basins were set in a certain place and
in John 19 verse 29
where they talk about a bowl of vinegar
being set and they took this this
vinegar to give to Jesus all of these
verses point to something intentionally
being set and the question is why would
God set Jesus Christ in a place to cause
people to stumble to fall in proverbs
chapter 16 verse 8 I want to show you
this because there's a reason why God
sent his son and set him up for us to
fall proverbs 16 and verse 8 well I
think that should be verse 18 proverbs
16 it should be verse 18 I'll just go
ahead and quoted pride goeth before what
destruction and a haughty spirit before
a fall so if the Bible is telling us
that Christ was set up for our fall it
appears then that the reason that Christ
has been set up for our fall is because
mankind struggles with an issue of pride
what do you think
are we being prideful no one is agreeing
with me yes mankind has an issue of
pride the Bible tells us whosoever
exalts himself shall be Watts shall be
humbled but he that humbles himself
shall be exalted in the book of Isaiah
chapter 8 verse 14 and 15 I want you to
notice this Isaiah chapter 8 verses 14
and 15 the Bible says there he that is
speaking of Christ shall be for a
sanctuary but a stone of stumbling a
stone of what everyone a stone of
stumbling and for a rock of Watts
a fence both to the houses of Israel and
for a jinn and for a snare
err to the inhabitants of Jerusalem so
the Bible's telling us here that Christ
would be set as a rock of offense and a
stumbling for those in Jerusalem notice
verse 15 and many among them shall watts
stumble and what else fall and what else
be broken and what else be snared and be
wants taken I want to focus on those
five things to stumble to fall to be
broken to be snared and to be taken why
would God want to set his son in a
position to cause mankind to stumble
first Peter chapter 2 verses 5 through 8
the Bible tells us this first Peter
chapter 2 verses 5 through 8 you also as
lively stones are built up a spiritual
house a holy priesthood to offer up
spiritual sacrifices acceptable to God
by Jesus Christ verse 6 wherefore also
it is contained in the scriptures behold
I what I lay what does that mean I
intentionally sex in Zion a chief
Cornerstone elect precious and he that
believeth on him shall not be was
confounded unto you therefore which
believe he is precious but unto them
which be disobedient the stone which the
builders disallowed the same has made
the head of the corner and notice verse
8 and the stone of what stumbling and a
rock of what's even to them would
stumble at the word being disobedient
where unto also they were appointed so
good news and bad news for those who
disbelieve this rock Jesus Christ is
what is a stumbling block but for those
who believe he is something precious
amen so how many of you came into this
world believing oh so we were all
disobedient at one time also the Bible
is right when it says all have one
sinned and fallen short of the glory of
God so all of us were on a road to
destruction all of us have sinned and so
now we understand that God sent his son
into this world to cause the disobedient
to stumble who were the disobedient
razor in every one of us were the
disobedient so Christ wants us to
stumble what pastor that sounds crazy
yes it is true God wants you to stumble
turn with me to Isaiah 59 or in fact
we're gonna look at it on the screen
Isaiah 59 verses one through three and
that four and then verse 7 the Bible
says behold the Lord's hand is not
shortened that it cannot save neither
he's here heavy that it cannot hear but
your Watts
iniquities have separated between you
and your God and your sins have hid his
face from you that he will not hear
verse 3 for your hands are Watts
defiled with blood and your fingers with
iniquity your lips have spoken lies your
tongue have muttered perverseness and
now notice verse 7 their feet their
whatever you want their what their feet
do what run - evil pause for a second
how many of you hate tripping when you
run you know tripping when you walk is
one thing you know you might trip like
walking up the steps and oh that's
always frustrating it's embarrassing but
to trip when you're running you know
what happens right don't be running on
concrete when you trip when you're
running that thing is is it's a
frustrating and painful thing why would
God want to trip us when we're running
because the Bible says the disobedient
run - what - evil
you guys do cats what God is doing when
you run to evil all you're doing is
running to hurt yourself
so God says I need to trip you up to
stop you from running to hurt yourself
and God will do that yes he will he will
stick his foot right there
and mess up your plans he will break
your truck down in front of a church
because he knew you you needed to be in
that church he will totally strip you up
mess up your plans just this morning
someone was sharing with me that they
had a plan they were going to commit
suicide you know what they got a gun and
shot themselves in the heart shot this
person shot himself in the heart and God
sure enough messed up his plans because
that person is here today that was God
tripping somebody up who was running to
what evil but loving this is what God
does because He loves us he's tripping
us up not because he wants to hurt us
but because he's trying to save us yes
he will send you to prison to set you
free he will do all kinds of things to
totally rip flip your plants because
very often beloved we like to go on our
own plans don't we so God says I'm gonna
I'm gonna cause you to stumble and how
does they do that he sets Jesus in the
way he sets Jesus in the way 1st
Corinthians 1 verse 23 I want you to
notice what it says 1st Corinthians
chapter 1 verse 23 the Bible says here
but we preach
oh Christ what crucified so when I say
Christ crucified what do you think of
you think of the cross check this out
guys the cross is the stumbling the
cross is what causes us to stumble this
my needs to say Amen he sent his son
into this world to die on the cross so
that when we come face to face with the
cross it causes us to stumble we preach
Christ crucified unto the Jews a
stumbling-block and unto the Greeks
foolishness so Christ wants us to
stumble why because he's trying to stop
us from running to evil but not only
does he want to system ball he wants us
to fall because you know sometimes you
stumble you catch yourself you ever do
one of those and the catch is a long
catch you not me you're stumbling in
your sight you're doing everything in
your power to like not finally hit the
floor and does and so we fight the
stumble haven't even know how to fight
the stumble yeah we fight the stumble we
don't want to fall but God wants us to
fall John 12 verse 24 listen to what
Jesus said here he said except a corn of
wheat what what fall into the ground and
die it abideth alone but if it die it
brings forth much fruit so we might
compare falling with dying God wants you
to die does God want you to die he sure
does he sure does he wants the old man
to die that's why he put the cross in
your way so that you could stumble and
not only stumble but also fall you see
the love that's why Jesus came to this
earth to die on our behalf
so that we could see what he did for us
and that love that amazing love that
Amazing Grace would stop us in our
tracks would cause us to stumble what
caused us to fall Jesus not only wants
us to fall he wants us to fall and be
broken notice with me Matthew 21 verse
42 to 44 Matthew 21 verses 42 to 44
jesus said unto them did you never read
in the scriptures the stone which the
builders rejected the same has become
the head of the corner this is the
Lord's doing and it is marvelous in our
sight therefore I say unto you the
kingdom of God shall be taken from you
speaking to the Jewish nation and given
to a nation bringing forth the fruits
thereof notice verse 44 and whosoever
shall fall on this stone shall be what's
broken but on whomsoever it shall fall
it will grind him to powder so watch
this beloved God not only wants you to
stumble he not only wants you to fall he
wants you to fall and break something he
wants you to fall and be broken anyone
ever fall and break something you're
running and you fall you break that leg
and now you're walking with that limp
God wants you to be broken what does it
mean to be broken it means to be humbled
first Peter chapter 5 verse 6 first
Peter chapter 5 verse 6 humble
yourselves therefore under the mighty
hand of God that he may walks
remember what I opening text said the
son of God is set for the fall and
rising again of many if we want to rise
we must first fall the Bible says in
Philippians 2:8 it tells us that Jesus
humbled himself and became obedient unto
the death of the Cross that's what it
means to fall God not only wants us to
stumble he not only wants us to fall he
not only wants us to be broken he wants
us to be snared you say pastor what does
it mean to be snared what are you saying
how can God want me to be snape snared
if you look at Luke chapter 5 verse 10
what does it mean to be snared what does
it mean to be snared don't look at the
screen what does it mean to be snared it
means to be captured wait God is setting
a trap for us watch these guys and so
was also James and and the son and John
the sons of Zebedee which were part of
the Simon Jesus said unto them fear not
from henceforth thou shalt thou so what
catch men now the Greek word therefore
catch it's actually translated as
ensnared let me ask you does God want to
ensnare men does God want to catch fish
that way okay now let's reverse does God
want to catch men yes so watch this when
he sets the cross in your path he is
planning that the cross will cause you
to stumble caused you to fall cause you
to be broken and that's how he catches
you
he ensnares you this is why Paul said
that he was a prisoner of Jesus Christ
because he was caught red-handed he was
caught and ensnared by the love of God
and finally he wants you to be taken
that's what we read in Isaiah 8 right
they would stumble fall be broken
captured and taken notice with me Isaiah
6 I'm sorry Psalm 68 verse 18 Psalm 68
verse 18 the Bible says doubt talking
about Jesus has ascended on high thou
has led captivity captive thou has
received gifts from 4 men
yay for the rebellious also that the
Lord God might dwell among them this
Texas tell
that Jesus when he ascended to heaven
took captives with him how many of you
would like to be taking with Jesus when
he comes again
are you want to be taken if you want to
be taken you first must be ensnared and
if you want to be ensnared you must be
broken
and if you want to be broken you have to
fall and if you want to fall you gotta
stumble and if you want any of that to
happen you got to go through Jesus
that's what he's calling us to do guys
he think that's why I set my son in your
path now we're coming around the bend
here we're coming to a close but I need
you to check this a few more verses
Romans chapter six verses one through
five the Bible says what shall we fix
say then shall we continue in sin that
grace may abound
god forbid how shall we that are dead to
sin live any longer therein verse 3 no
you not that so many of us as were
baptized into Jesus Christ were baptized
into his death verse 4 therefore we are
buried with him by baptism into death
that like his cries was Christ was
raised up from the dead pause for a
second what is baptism what happens in
Baptism two things happen I'm looking
for two words specifically in a very
literal sense when someone is in the
baptismal pool two things happen to them
they fall and they rise they fall and
they rise and this falling and rising is
a symbol of a new creature being born
it's a symbol of conversion this is what
God is doing notice with me 1st Peter
chapter 2 verse 1 through 5 because in
1st Peter chapter 2 verses 1 through 5
the Bible says 1st Peter chapter 2 verse
1 wherefore laying aside all malice now
I want you to check this out how do you
lay aside all malice how many of you
how many of you want to guess what that
word laying laying aside it's an
intentional sitting down but the
question is how do you how do you lay
aside how do you drop the stuff you were
kick the sins you are carrying before
how do you drop them let's keep reading
verse verse two wherefore as newborn
babes desire the sincere milk of the
word that you may grow thereby if so
that you have tasted the Lord is
gracious verse four
so whom coming out onto a living stone
disallowed indeed of men but chosen of
God and precious verse five you also as
lively stones are built up a spiritual
house pause for a second you once had
malice but now you dropped malice why
did you drop malice has anyone ever
tricked while you were carrying
something this is a book bag something
so imagine running with something and
you trick what happens to the stuff you
were carrying when you were running when
you trip you drop it you drop it Christ
becomes a stumbling block so that we can
trip and drop our sins because when we
trip and drop our sins we have laid them
aside and God can do the work he desires
to do in us God sent his son into this
world to trip you up that's good news
guys when we think this season and the
birth of Christ the Bible says let us
lay aside the weight or the sin that
does so easily beset us this is what
he's calling us to do he's calling us to
lay aside he's calling us to not be
afraid to stumble and fall and allow
Jesus to take control of our lives
that's why he came into this world
so I got two stories to close for you to
close with number one do you member
gentleman by the name of Jacob you know
what happened when Jacob was returning
back to his home and he runs into an
angel which is really which is really
gamma was Jesus and the Bible says that
Jacob in his fear grabs hold of this
angel and they begin to wrestling
remember that story and you know many of
us we don't like wrestling much less
wrestling with God because that's what
God has come into this world to do he's
come into this world to wrestle with us
to stop us from doing some of the crazy
things that we often think of doing
either to ourselves or to others because
that's what sin does it leads you to do
crazy things so God is wrestling with
Jacob and the morning is about to come
and then Jacob says or God says let me
go and Jacob is like no I'm not letting
you go I'm not letting you go and then
you know what you know what God finally
does what does he do he touches the
hollow of his thigh and all of a sudden
Jacob goes experiences this intense pain
and he still refuses to do one let go
god bless him and you know what he does
he changes his name the man so what is
the name change signifying does that
signify new birth signifies new birth
doesn't it but the result the evidence
of the name change was that Jacob was
now crippled he walked with a limp so in
my mind he was probably walked like this
maybe not but he had the limp the
evidence of his conversion was in the
limp
where is your limp
do you have one because that's the sign
that you have wrestled with God that's
the sign that you have stumbled and
fallen and broke something and what is
broken is the old you that's what the
limp signifies it's the owe you so now
when people get mad at you you know it's
okay I got a limp the things that you
once used to love to do now you can't do
those things anymore because yeah you
know I've got a limb in fact when the
Bible says let us run with patience the
race that is set before us you ought to
be running with a limp that should be
the evidence that God has made you into
a new person one more story I promise
you see I'm coming down here see how
many remember a man by the name of a
fibber said you're that guy remember how
when he was 5 years old he was
Jonathan's son he was 5 years old and
after a saw had been killed his nurse
takes him up and she's running with him
and what happened to them he fell and
became lame and so many years later
David is his key and he's looking for
someone to bless in the house of Saul
and he learns about Jonathan's son
Mephibosheth and he sends for him and he
says come and you can imagine what this
lame man is thinking he's thinking is
the king after me to destroy me because
he knows I'm of the house of Saul what
was David seeking to do he was seeking
to bless him and the Bible says he
brought him into his own home and he
said you're gonna eat at the Kings table
from now on and
we'll be as one of the king's sons
beloved when you become crippled God
invites you to his table that's
ultimately what he's after he's just
trying to stop you stop me stop us from
hurting ourselves by running to evil it
might look like something worthy to
chase after man I want this guy in my
life man I want this woman in my life
man I really want this job and you might
wonder why the god shut the door to that
job why does it seem like God always
messes up my plans it's because he loves
you
it's because he loves you how many of
you want to stumble how many of you want
to fall and then you're like yeah yeah
yeah you get what I'm asking right we
want to fall on that rock how many of
you want to be broken
yes but of it this is what God is after
stop running away from him and start
running toward him alone I'm gonna
invite you up to come and lead us in
prayer and I'm gonna invite you where
you are if you can kneel as low low
praise let us seek the Lord's face